Darragh Martin

Tel: 087 781 0773 daradona10@gmail.com

Have just completed a Full Stack Software Development Framework Course from the Code Institute in Dublin giving me excellent training in the software development lifecycle, covering topics such as HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, SQL, AWS, Python, Django, Mongo DB and User Experience Design (UXD)

In my professional life I have a gained wealth of customer focus, IT and managerial experience from working in the gaming industry for over 15 years. I have recruited and mentored junior employees. I am an open-minded and hard-working team player with excellent communication skills, great attention to detail and an analytical approach to problem solving.

Education & Certifications

Diploma in Software Development International Management in Entrepreneurship	2020 2005	Code Institute Dublin University of Limerick
Bachelor of Arts in International Business Hons.	2002	American College Dublin
		Lynn University Florida
Leaving Certificate	1997	St. Clements College Limerick
		Rockwell College, Tipperary

Diploma in Software Development Projects:

Project 1: Developed a gym membership website which was built using HTML5, CSS3, and Bootstrap framework along with some jQuery for interactivity.

Project 2: Created a website for the EURO 2020 Football Championships which alongside using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery, JavaScript, EmailJS and the Google Maps API

Project 3: Programmed a cookbook recipe website that allowed users to view recipes, preparation methods, edit and delete recipes and their ingredients. The website was developed with the Flask Framework, HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript connecting to a MongoDB database and Python at the back end.

Project 4: Developed a fully functioning sports product e-commerce website. Technologies used were the Django Framework, Postgres database, Python, HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript. Heroku was used to deploy it and Travis CI for build testing along with AWS 3 for hosting of static and media files.

Professional Experience

Oct 2016 - Dec 2019

Director/Company Secretary

Marko Ltd, Limerick

Spent 2 years in a Director role for this leader in the gaming and leisure industry and was instrumental in the very successful sale of the company's business as a going concern as well as an associated property portfolio. Other relevant project successes:

- Implemented the latest software systems on all the gaming machines allowing synchronisation of real time data to the main company database.
- Overhauled the company's customer database to comply with latest GDPR regulations.
- Incorporated computer applications as required on company servers to showcase company profit and loss data and future projections. Regularly applied latest machine software patches.

Aug 2013 – Sep 2016

General Manager

Marko Ltd, Limerick

Worked for 3 years as General Manager for Marko Ltd. taking charge of all casino operations and IT network systems. Successful IT projects during this time:

- Interacted with other IT specialists around Europe to rectify company server issues.
- Successfully introduced a complete technical revamp of systems to harness accounting feedback from individual gambling machines
- Linked all gaming machines to online jackpot system

Jul 2005 – Jul 2013

Floor Manager

Marko Ltd, Limerick

As Floor Manager for Marko Ltd, my main roles were as casino supervisor, customer liaison officer, casino equipment technician and staff liaison officer. My notable successes in this role were:

- Devised cash control and accounting systems to assist in assessing and reconciling the performance of diverse casino equipment.
- Implemented weekly MS Excel spreadsheet management accounting reports.
- Performed day to day banking duties control including preparation of lodgements, invoice payments to suppliers and weekly payroll.

May 2002 - Oct 2002

Internship

Irish Life & Permanent, Dublin

Worked for 6 months for this leader in banking on their Intern program. Key responsibilities included:

- Weekly board meetings to discuss various issues that needed addressing
- Worked with key groups to implement the Irish Life Census forms to all their employees over the country and to record this data in their database system
- Worked with other departments from HR to Accounting to implement various interdepartmental data synchronisation projects